

jacob.kim.johnson@gmail.com

wordstosong.me

in/jacobkimjohnson

PHONE

(608)790-7675

LOCATION

Los Angeles, CA

I'm a UX/UI designer, graphic designer, and programmer with a deep passion for the creative process. Having a strong desire for problemsolving, my creativity, thoughtfulness, critical thinking, and collaborative nature have been beneficial as strengths, both personally and professionally. I have worked for organizations both large and small and spanning different industries, which has given me the distinct ability to examine situations and consider strategies from different perspectives. It has helped me be more open-minded as I figure out the details, while focusing on the big picture.

JACOB KIM JOHNSON

EXPERIENCE

UX/UI Designer, **Graphic Designer**, and Web Developer Self-employed Aug. 2017 - Present

- Challenged visual web layout skills by designing and developing user-centric, mobile-first web apps from scratch (using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript)
- Created wireframes and mockups of web app designs
- Refined typography execution with font pairings, hierarchy, and spacing
- Refined other aspects of visual design, like color theory and visual hierarchy/ spacing
- Designed and created graphics for logos and web content
- Researched ongoing design trends, both in UX/UI and visual composition

Graphic Designer, Web Content Coordinator, and UX/UI Designer **CBE** International Jul. 2014 - Sep. 2017

- Helped plan, research, test, and implement website functionality and design to improve user experience for conversion-oriented interface
- Created wireframes and mockups of web pages for updates and redesigns
- Created UX user personas and conceptualized journey maps
- Designed logo concepts for the organization's main brand and blog
- Created graphic images for internal (e.g. web headers) and external (e.g. advertisements) purposes
- Designed and edited printed marketing materials and book covers/layouts
- Coordinated with all departments and developers to ensure brand and visual consistency
- Edited and managed web content with Drupal CMS and HTML/CSS
- Improved social media strategies to be more visual, better suit reader interest, and increase interaction

Marketing Specialist (Contractor)

CATS Software, Inc. Apr. 2014 - Jul. 2014

- Experienced Agile methodology with daily meetings and JIRA for project management
- Created icons, graphics, and cartoons as companions to blog articles and social media posts
- Managed social media accounts and helped facilitate conversation for start-up organization
- Wrote industry relevant blog articles to help push organizational narrative voice

Marketing Intern High Noon Saloon Jun. 2010 - Jun. 2011

- Edited website design to improve clarity of information
- Created graphics for upcoming events to manage and share via social media
- Wrote and edited content for the website, regarding upcoming events

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts Luther College **Graduated May 2010** Major: Business Management

Minor: Psychology

Emphasis: Marketing

Certificate

Minneapolis Community and Technical College Completed Dec. 2014

- Graphic Design
- Web Design

SKILLED WITH

Photoshop Illustrator InDesign Sketch Invision Axure